localwise.com 2019-03-20

# Privacy Policy - Localwise

* * *

#### Introduction

Localwise Inc., ("Localwise," "we," "our," or "us") values your privacy. In this Privacy Policy ("Policy"), we describe the information we collect, how we use it, and when and with whom we share it. This Policy applies to all sites, mobile applications, and other online services (collectively, "Platform") made available by Localwise. This Policy applies only to information collected on or through the Platform. It does not apply to information collected or obtained by or through any other means (including, without limitation, information collected offline, in person, over the telephone and/or by mail, or from third parties outside the Platform). Undefined capitalized terms used herein shall have the definitions as set forth in our Terms of Use.

#### Consent

By accessing or using Localwise, you agree to this Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not access or use Localwise.

#### Information We Collect

We collect information in multiple ways including when you provide information directly to us, when you permit third parties to provide information to us, and when we passively collect information from you, such as information collected from your browser or device.

We may collect information from you during your use or access of the Platform, such as when you: (a) register; (b) complete a personal and/or business profile; (c) post a job; (d) apply for a job; (e) share information about other users or businesses; (f) invite people or businesses to join the Platform; (g) participate in polls or surveys; (h) sign up for electronic newsletters or other electronic communication; (i) make a purchase; (j) fill out any forms; (k) enter a sweepstakes or contest; (l) register for a promotion; (m) transmit User Content; (n) otherwise communicate with us or other users through the Platform or, (o) authorize Localwise to connect your account to the account of a “Connected Site” (for example, Facebook or Google). This list is illustrative, not exhaustive; the Privacy Policy applies to all use of the Platform.

The information you provide directly to us may concern you or others and may include, but is not limited to: (a) name; (b) zip code; (c) email address; (d) home or business telephone number; (e) home, business or mailing address; (f) demographic information (e.g., gender, age, political preference, education, race or ethnic origin, and other information relevant to user surveys and/or offers); (g) date of birth; (h) business or organization name; (i) photographs; (j) skills, work experience, and/or educational experience; (k) video or audio files; (l) recommendations or endorsements to or from you; and/or (m) in certain circumstances, payment and/or identity verification information. You are not required to provide us with such information, but certain features of the Platform may not be accessible or available, absent the provision of the requested information.

**_Information from Affiliates, Social Networking Sites, and other Non-affiliated Third Parties_**

We may collect information about you or others through Localwise affiliates or through non-affiliated third parties. For example, you may be able to access the Platform through Facebook or Google. If you access the Platform through your Facebook account, you may allow us to have access to certain information in your Facebook profile. This may include your name, profile picture, gender, networks, user IDs, list of friends, connections, or contacts, location, date of birth, email address, photos, videos, people you follow and/or who follow you, and/or your posts or "likes."

Sites such as Facebook or Google have their own policies for handling your information. For a description of how these sites may use and disclose your information including any information you make public, please consult the sites' privacy policies. We have no control over how any third-party site uses or discloses the personal information it collects about you.

We may also collect information about you or others through non-affiliated third parties. For example, to the extent permitted by law, we may, in our sole discretion, ask for and collect supplemental information from third parties, such as information about your credit from a credit bureau, or information to verify your identity or trustworthiness, or for other fraud or safety protection purposes. We may combine information that we collect from you through the Platform with information that we obtain from such third parties and information derived from any other products or services we provide.

**_Information That is Passively or Automatically Collected_**

**_Device/Usage Information._** We and our third-party service providers, which include ad networks and analytics companies (such as Google Analytics), may use cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies to collect information about the computers or devices (including mobile devices) you use to access the Platform. As described further below, we may collect and analyze information including but not limited to (a) browser type; (b) ISP or operating system; (c) domain name; (d) access time; (e) referring or exit pages; (f) page views; (g) IP address; (h) unique device identifiers (e.g. IDFA or Android ID); and (i) the type of device that you use. We may also track how frequently you access or use the Platform. We use this information (including the information collected by our third-party service providers) for Platform analytics (including to determine which portions of the Platform are used most frequently and what our users like/do not like), to assist in determining relevant advertising (both on and off the Platform), to evaluate the success of our advertising campaigns, and as otherwise described in this Policy. 

**_Location Information._** When you use the Platform, we may collect general location information (such as IP address). If you install our mobile app, we may ask you to grant us access to your mobile device's geolocation data. If you grant such permission, we may collect information about your precise geolocation, and we may use that information to improve the Platform, including providing you with location-based features (e.g. for identification of jobs near you). To deliver customized content and advertising, we may share your location information with our agents, vendors, or advertisers. If you access the Platform through a mobile device and you do not want your device to provide us with location-tracking information, you can disable the GPS or other location-tracking functions on your device, provided your device allows you to do this. See your device manufacturer's instructions for further details. If you disable certain functions, you may be unable to use certain parts of the Platform. 

**_Cookies and Other Electronic Technologies._** We and our third-party service providers may use cookies, clear GIFs, pixel tags, and other technologies that help us better understand user behavior, personalize preferences, perform research and analytics, and improve the Platform. These technologies, for example, may allow us to tailor the Platform to your needs, save your password in password-protected areas, track the pages you visit, help us manage content, and compile statistics about Platform usage. We also use certain of these technologies to deliver job advertisements or other advertisements through the Platform that may interest you. We or our third-party service providers also may use certain of these technologies in emails to our customers to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed, and track whether our emails are forwarded. 

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but your browser may allow you to modify your browser settings to decline cookies if you prefer. If you disable cookies, you may be prevented from taking full advantage of the Platform, because it may not function properly. As we adopt additional technologies, we may also gather additional information through other methods. 

#### How We Use The Information We Collect

We may use your information for any of the following reasons:

  * For the purposes for which you provided it;
  * To enable you to use the services available through the Platform, including registering you for our services and verifying your identity and authority to use our services;
  * To match Job Seekers and Employers;
  * To facilitate user communication that you initiate including, but not limited to, messages or request for a recommendation;
  * For customer support and to respond to your inquiries;
  * For internal record-keeping purposes;
  * To administer surveys, sweepstakes, promotions, or contests;
  * To process billing and payment including sharing with third-party payment gateways and payment service providers in connection with the Platform;
  * To provide you with notices about your account and/or your subscription, including expiration and renewal notices;
  * To improve our Platform and the services by enabling us to: store information about your preferences, allowing us to deliver a more personalized service to you; speed up your searches; and recognize you when you return to the Platform;
  * To diagnose service or technical problems, trouble shooting, analyzing how our services is used, personalizing content for you, providing the end service to you (which may include sharing certain information with third party vendors and service providers) and to respond to any enquiries that you may have;
  * To address fraud or safety concerns, or to investigate complaints or suspected fraud or wrongdoing;
  * To periodically send promotional emails or other information that may interest you;
  * With your consent, to contact you by text message regarding certain services or information you have requested;
  * With your consent, to contact you by telephone or text message regarding Platform features, improvements, or other products and services that may interest you;
  * For Localwise's market research purposes, including, but not limited to, the customization of the Platform according to your interests;
  * To contact you about goods and services that may interest you or with information about your use of the Platform;
  * For other research and analytical purposes;
  * To resolve disputes, to protect ourselves and other users of the Platform, and to enforce any legal terms that govern your use of the Platform;
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information; and
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

We may combine information that we collect from you through the Platform with information that we obtain from affiliated and nonaffiliated third parties, and information derived from any other products or services we provide.

We may aggregate and/or de-identify information collected through the Platform. We may use de-identified or aggregated data for any purpose, including without limitation for research and marketing purposes and may also share such data with any third parties, including without limitation, advertisers, promotional partners, sponsors, event promoters, and/or others.

Any personal information or content that you voluntarily disclose for public posting to our services, such as User Content, becomes available to the public and may be accessed, used and stored by other around the world. Accordingly, you should not post sensitive personal information or any other information that you would not want made public to any other site or application or to a public website. You should never provide your social security number, national insurance number, financial information, passport number, and other sensitive information.

We may also use your information to contact you about our own and third-parties' goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, please check the relevant box located on the form on which we collect your data, adjust your user preferences and /or click "Unsubscribe" in any e-mail communications we send you. You cannot opt-out of services-related notices. Opting out may prevent you from receiving email messages regarding updates, improvements, offers, or new features or functionality.

#### When We Disclose Your Information

Unless otherwise described in this Policy, we may also share the information that we collect from you through the Platform as follows:

  * **_Affiliates._** We may share your information with any Localwise affiliates.
  * **_Services._** To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it. For example, with prospective employers and recruiters if you respond to a job postings. Additionally, if you give us an e-mail address to use the "vouch" feature of our Platform, we will transmit the contents of that vouch e-mail and your e-mail address to the recipients.
  * **_Consent._** We may disclose your information to nonaffiliated third parties based on your consent to do so. Such consent includes the disclosure of your information (a) in order to provide services or products that you have requested; (b) when we have your permission; or (c) as described in this Policy, the Terms of Use, or any other legal terms governing your use of the Platform.
  * **_Service Providers._** We may provide access to your information to select third parties who perform services on our behalf. These third parties provide a variety of services to us including without limitation billing, customer service, sales, marketing, analytics, email services, advertising, market research, fulfillment, data storage, analysis and processing, identity verification, fraud and safety protection and legal services. We may also authorize third party vendors to collect information on our behalf, including as necessary to operate certain features of our Platform or to facilitate the delivery of online advertising tailored to your interests. As we retain new service providers, we generally seek contractual assurances from these service providers that they will not use your information in any manner other than to help us provide you with the services and products available from Localwise.
  * **_Legal Requirements._** We may disclose your information when required by law or when we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to: (a) comply with subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process we receive; (b) establish or exercise our legal rights including enforcing and administering agreements with users; or (c) defend Localwise against legal claims. If we are required by law to disclose your information, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to notify you unless we believe in our sole discretion that (a) providing notice is prohibited by the legal process itself, court order or applicable law; or (b) we, in our sole discretion, believe that providing notice could create a risk of injury or death, or that harm or fraud could be directed to Localwise or users. We will attempt to provide the notice by email if you have given us an email address. If you do not challenge the disclosure request, we may be legally required to turn over your information.
  * **_Protection of Localwise and Others._** We may disclose your information when we believe it appropriate to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of the Terms of Use or any other legal terms governing use of the Platform, and/or to protect our rights and property and the rights and property of other users.
  * **_Business Transfers._** As we continue to develop our business, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses, or sell some or all of our assets. In such transactions or where there is any change of control of Localwise, user information may be among the transferred assets.
  * **_Academics and Research._** We may provide information about users to third parties for academic and research purposes, in anonymized or aggregated form. 

Please be advised that some information you provide will be publicly accessible. 

For instance, registration for an Account requires that you provide us with your name. If you register through Facebook or Google, the Platform will use the name associated with your Facebook or Google account. Your name may be visible to other users. Depending on the circumstances, your name may be attached to your job applications, personal profile, and/or various business profiles. Certain other people, including other users with whom you have interacted via the Platform, will see information about you that is attached to your name. You may limit the users who can see your personal information in your Localwise account settings.

We also offer a “public profile” feature that allows your personal profile and/or business profile to be indexed and displayed through public search engines. You may opt out of this feature in your Localwise account settings. 

We invite you to post Content on or through our Platform. However, please be careful and responsible whenever you are online. If you choose to post content on or through the Platform, that information: (a) may be or become publicly available; (b) may be collected and used by third parties without our knowledge; and (c) may be used in a manner that may violate this Policy, the law, or your personal privacy. All materials or content posted to public areas of the Platform are public. As such, Localwise assumes no liability for the accuracy of such information, no duty to update or correct such information, and no liability for such communications arising under the laws of copyright, libel, privacy, obscenity, or otherwise.

#### Third Party Web Sites

Except as otherwise discussed in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. Other websites accessible through our Platform have their own privacy policies and data collection, use and disclosure practices. Please consult each website's privacy policy. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties. Additionally, other companies which place advertising on our Platform may collect information about you when you view or click on their advertising through the use of cookies. We cannot control this collection of information. You should contact these advertisers directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect.

#### California's Shine the Light Law

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our customers who are California residents to request and obtain from us a list of what personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the names and addresses of those third parties. Requests may be made only once a year and are free of charge.

#### Children’s Privacy

If you are under the age of sixteen (16), we strongly encourage you to use Localwise only with the knowledge of a parent or guardian. Any information you submit will be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Localwise will never knowingly gather personal information from anyone under the age of 13, in compliance with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act. (see: www.coppa.org/)

#### Security

We employ appropriate security measures, which are reasonably designed to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access or disclosure. Localwise may use encryption, passwords, and physical security measures to help protect your personal information against unauthorized access and disclosure. No security measures, however, are 100% failsafe. Therefore, we do not promise and cannot guarantee, and thus you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will not be collected, disclosed and/or used by others. While we strive to protect your personal information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) the security, integrity and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through this Platform cannot be guaranteed; and (c) any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, keeping your log-in and password private, and not recycling passwords from other websites or accounts. Localwise is not responsible for the unauthorized use of your information nor for any lost, stolen, compromised passwords, or for any activity on your Account via unauthorized password activity.

#### Links to External Platforms

The Platform may contain links to other websites or resources over which Localwise does not have any control. Such links do not constitute an endorsement by Localwise of those external websites. You acknowledge that Localwise is providing these links to you only as a convenience, and further agree that Localwise is not responsible for the content of such external websites or the protection and privacy of information you provide while visiting such external websites.

#### Updating, Deleting, and Correcting Your Information

You may review, correct and delete certain information about you. Upon your request, we will close your Account and remove your profile information from view as soon as reasonably possible. We may retain information from closed Accounts in order to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations of any user, enforce our Terms of Use, and/or for any other purposes otherwise permitted by law that we deem necessary in our sole discretion. You should understand, however, that once you transmit User Content through the Platform, you may not be able to change or remove it. Once we have deleted or removed your Account, you agree that Localwise will not be responsible to you for retaining information related to your Account.

#### Your Choices Regarding Email Communications

We may send periodic informational or promotional emails to you directly or through third party services. These messages will be sent to you based on your profile information, use of Localwise, and messaging preferences. You may change your email and contact preferences at any time. If you opt out of receiving emails about jobs or other information we think may interest you, we may still send you emails about your Account or administrative, transactional and/or legal messages.

#### Changes to This Policy

This policy is current as of the effective date set forth below. Localwise may, in its sole and absolute discretion, change this policy at any time. Localwise will posts its updated policy on the Platform or send you an email in advance of the new effective date. We encourage you to review this Policy regularly for any changes. Your continued access to or use of the Platform will be subject to the terms of the then-current policy. 

#### Terms of Use

Please also visit our Terms of Use section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our Platform.

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions about the Privacy Policy or the Platform, please contact us by sending an email to [hello@localwise.com](mailto:hello@localwise.com).

#####  Effective Date: October 9, 2017   
Last Update: October 9, 2017   
Copyright © 2019 Localwise Inc.; All rights reserved.
